(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T01:44:44.256425",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
イッツショウタイム
It's showtime!
セカイはまだ始まってすらない
The world hasn't even begun yet.
イッツショウタイム
It's showtime!
セカイはまだ始まってすらない
The world hasn't even begun yet.
魔法使いのキャストも
Even the cast of wizards,
トラウマ背負った怪物も
And monsters carrying trauma,
いつかみんないなくなること知ってる
Know that everyone will disappear someday.
期限切れのチケットと
With expired tickets,
経年劣化するハートビート
And a heartbeat that deteriorates with age,
「未来、また来ようね」って
Saying, "Let's come again next year,"
約束を果たせずに
Without fulfilling the promise,
もうダメかも？
Maybe we're done for?
それハウマッチ？
How much is that?
ノイズばっか増える
Only noise keeps increasing.
素直に感動したいよ ずっとそうだった
I want to be honestly moved, it's always been like that.
錆びた廃屋で夢を見てる
Dreaming in a rusted abandoned house.
終わりを超えてずっとパリピ
Party people forever beyond the end.
回り続けるメリーゴーランド
The merry-go-round keeps spinning.
セカイはまだ始まってすらないぜ
The world hasn't even begun yet!
毎分毎秒毎秒に絶望まぶしてさ
Sprinkling despair into every minute and second,
地獄の底でハッピーエンドを
A happy ending at the bottom of hell.
セカイはまだ始まってすらないぜ
The world hasn't even begun yet!
無神経な王様も
Even the insensitive king,
欲にまみれたアルケミストも
Even the greed-stained alchemist,
いつか土に還っていく 未練を残したまま
Someday returning to dust, leaving behind my regrets...
やばい 神かも
Man, I might be a god.
それフェイクニュース？
Is that fake news?
争いばっか 争いばっか 塞んでる
Just fighting, just fighting, shutting it out.
知恵の輪は解きたいよ ずっと不安だった
I want to solve the puzzle ring, I've been anxious all along.
埃払って 再起動する
Wipe off the dust and reboot.
寿命のセマフォと 人生を
With the semaphore of lifespan and life,
星空駆ける ジェットコースターを
A rollercoaster racing across the starry sky.
セカイはまだ 始まってすらいないぜ
The world hasn't even begun yet!
最悪で最高な 予想外を
An unexpected twist that's the worst and best.
例えばと塗り替える ブラウスを
Repainting the blouse with a "what if".
セカイはまだ 始まってすらいないぜ
The world hasn't even begun yet!
終わりを超えて ずっとパーティーを
Transcending the end, partying on forever.
回り続ける メリーゴーランドを
A merry-go-round that keeps spinning.
セカイはまだ 始まってすらいないぜ
The world hasn't even begun yet!
壊せよ膠着の 未来を
Break the stagnant future!
鳴らせ再生を告げる 鐘を
Ring the bell announcing rebirth!
セカイはまだ 始まってすらいないぜ
The world hasn't even begun yet!
イッツ・ショウタイム
It's showtime!
はえーというわけで
Phew, so that's why...
みなののこんばんわでござる 見てるかい？
Good evening, lords and ladies. Are you watching?
ホロライブ6期生 ホロックスの用心棒 侍の
Hololive 6th Generation, HoloX's bodyguard, the samurai...
風真いろはでござる 見ぬのだの見てるか？
...Kazama Iroha is here! Are you watching, everyone?
あ、めちゃコメント見えてる！ すご！ めちゃ流れてる！ やっほー！
Ah, I can see so many comments! Wow! They're scrolling so fast! Yahoo!
たくさんこんなに 動けるように なりましたー！
I'm so glad I can move around this much now!
先輩たちもね 稼げたくさん立っていたこのホロアリーナでね 足をつけ
On this Holo Arena where many seniors stood, I planted my feet
一曲目歌えたでござる ありがとう 2Dになったよ
and was able to sing my first song! Thank you, I became 2D—
すごいよ よかった！
I mean 3D! It's so great, yay!
ちょっとまだね 他にもいっぱいやる事あるから ちょっと体力残しといて
Hold on, I still have a lot of other things to do, so I need to save some stamina.
はい というわけで改めて
Yes, so once again...
風真いろは3Dで ツイッターたくさんつぶやいてくださいね！ よろしくお願いします！
Please tweet a lot with #KazamaIroha3D! Thank you very much!
今日はねでもなんかたくさん見せたいことがありすぎて 1時間っていう枠が足りるかすごく心配なんですけど
Today, you know, there's just so much I want to show you, I'm really worried if a one-hour slot will be enough.
ま まずはね 早速 やっぱね風真といえばフィジカルということで動いてるとこいっぱい見せたいなと思うんで
Well, first of all, right away, as expected of Kazama, physical activity is our thing, so I want to show you plenty of me moving around.
いつもね 修業している道場のほうに最初に移動して このね 訓練の様子を見せていきたいなと思います。
First, I'll move over to the dojo where I usually train, and show you how my training goes.
それでは風真の道場へ レッツ・ゴー！いくでー！わー！
Now then, to Kazama's dojo, let's go! Let's do it! Wah!
はーい みなどの お待たせでござる
Hiii, lords and ladies, sorry to keep you waiting!
カメラ カメラが カメラ あ お カメラ！ めちゃくちゃひどいな カメラ！
Camera, the camera! Camera, ah, oh, camera! That's awful, camera!
あれ 風真ちょっとこれ ちゃんと映ってないとね 足しか 足しか映ってないでござる！
Huh, Kazama, if this doesn't capture properly... only my legs, only my legs are on screen!
ちょっと ちょっと映してくれ 映してくれ よいよ よいよ
Hold on, show me properly, show me! There we go, there we go!
ちょっとさんにカメラを渡して
Hand the camera to Chotto-san
こっちに来るんでござる。おいで！
and come over here. Come, come!
おいで、おいで、おいで。おお、来た来た来た来た来た！
Come, come, come! Oh, they're coming!
おお、よくがんばったでござるな、ポコべ。
Oh, you did your best, Pokobe!
えらい、えらい！えらいでござるよ。
Good job, good job! You're so good.
えらいで、ポコべ。えらいよ。えらい、えらい、えらい、えらい。
Good boy, Pokobe. Such a good boy!
はい！じゃあ、ちょっとね、ここにおいで。
Okay! Now then, come over here.
よいしょっと。はい。
Heave-ho. There we go.
はい、というわけでね、皆様の改めまして！今日は3Dお披露目配信に来てくださって、
Yes! So everyone, once again... Thank you so much
ありがとうございます！イエーイ！
for coming to my 3D debut stream! Yay!
あ、じゃあポコべが、ポコべが映るね。イエーイ！見てるでござるか？見てますか？見てますか？
And Pokobe is showing on screen too. Yay! Are you watching?
はい、1曲目でいきなりちょっと歌って送らせていただいたでござるが、どうだったでしょうか？
Yes, I suddenly sang a song for the first track, but how was it?
顔が、顔が、今日そうだった？
Was my face like that today?
お、かっこいいしょ？お、かっこいいって言って、もっかい！え、かっこいいって！
Oh, look cool, right? Say it again, "You look cool!"
はい！でね、ちょっと改めてね、風真のね、こともっともっと良く見たいって思ってくれてる方々が多いと思うので、
Yes! And so, once again, since many of you probably want to see more and more of Kazama,
紹介をね、していこうと思います。はい。
I'd like to introduce a few things. Yes.
で、ポコべはみたいでしょ？で、ポコべでね、これ、ポコべー！
And you want to see Pokobe, right? So with Pokobe, here—Pokobe!
かわいい！ポコべ！ちょ、おっ、おっ、ちょ、待っ、えっ、ちょ、カメラ、ちょ、ちょ、ポコべ、ポコべ、ポコべ、どうする、ポコべーー！
Cute, Pokobe! Wait, camera, wait, Pokobe, what do we do, Pokobe?!
どうするって。ポコべ！
What do you mean, what do we do? Pokobe!
でかい！でかいよ！
So big! So big!
急に、急に大きくなるじゃん！どうした、成長期か？
All of a sudden, you got so huge! What's wrong, a growth spurt?
ちょ、踏まれる、踏まれる、風真、踏まれるんだけど。
Wait, I'm gonna get stepped on, Kazama's gonna get stepped on!
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。ポコべ急に大きくなったでござるな。
Heave-ho. Pokobe, you got big all of a sudden.
ちょっと風真立っても同じぐらいあるんじゃない？
Aren't you about the same height as me standing up?
おお、すごい！ちょ、見て、巨大ポコべ！巨大ポコべ、ちょっと、ちょっといいですか？自分、巨大ポコべ吸い、いいですか？ちょっと1回やってみたかったんだよね。
Oh, wow! Look, giant Pokobe! Is this okay? Can I try inhaling giant Pokobe?
ちょ、いいよな。ほっ！
It should be fine, right? Ha!
はー！よいしょー！ポコべ！ポコべいいぞ、ちょっと回、行け。ポコべ！よっ！
Heave-ho! Pokobe! Pokobe, that's it, go around, go. Pokobe! Yo!
すうすうすうすうすうすうすうすう。ふいー！
*Inhaling sounds* Phew!
ありがとうな、ポコべ吸わせてくれて。ね、かわいいでしょ、ポコべ。
Thanks for letting me inhale you, Pokobe. Right, isn't Pokobe cute?
どう？お、小さくなった。ちょっと待って、急に自分がスポットライト当てられるとなんか、ちょっと恥ずかしくなっちゃうの。ちょ、小さくなりすぎでしょ！
How's—oh, they got smaller. Wait, suddenly getting the spotlight... What? I get embarrassed!
ちょっと！あなた、あなた豆ポコべになってますよ。ちょっと、だめでござるよ。
Hey! You, you've become a bean Pokobe. That's no good.
もうちょっと、もうちょっと、もうちょっと、もうちょっと……もうちょっと、もっともっとって。いつもみたいにね。あ、そうそうそう。いいね、いいね。そのぐらいね。
A bit more... Like usual, right? Ah, yes. Good, good. About that much.
はい、えっと、ポコべ堪能した？あれ、おかしいな、これ風真の3Dお披露目の話なのに、なんかポコべのほうを見せてる気がする。
Did you enjoy Pokobe? Wait, this is supposed to be my 3D debut stream, right?
じゃあちょっとね、そろそろ風真のね、全身も見ていこうかな。
Well then, let's look at Kazama's full body as well.
じゃじゃーん！ちょっと待って、待って、待って。カメラ、めちゃめちゃ近いじゃん！カメラ、めちゃめちゃ近いじゃん！ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って。
Ta-da! Wait, the camera is so close! The camera is way too close!
ホントに近いんだけど。ちょっと待って。ちょっと待って。心のBPMが上がってきてるので、ちょっと1回準備しますね。
I'm really close to it. Hang on. My mental BPM is rising, so let me prepare.
ふー。よいしょっと。よいしょ。よし、オッケー。
Phew. Heave-ho. Heave-ho. Okay, good.
お待たせ！はい、じゃあ、みんな、みんな、ちょっと見て。
Thanks for waiting! Yes, everyone, please take a look.
どうですか？どうですか？いろんなね、ほうかく、ほうかく、ほうこうから見れるようになりました！
How is it? You can now view me from all sorts of directions and angles!
でも、いつもいつも前からしか見てないからさ、風真の全身と一緒にもっと見てもらうって思ってくれてる方々が多いと思うので、ポコべも一緒にね。ポコべも一緒に連れながら、ちょっとね、見せて、見てこれ！
Since you've only seen me from the front, I thought you'd want to see my full body along with Pokobe!
初めて後ろ公開するんでござるが、ぽにーてーる、そう、風真のポニーテール、実は結構短めだったんでござるよ。
It's the first time I'm revealing my back, but the ponytail—yes, Kazama's ponytail is quite short.
ここまでしかいないんだけど、ここまでしかないんだけど。
It only goes up to here.
えと、そう。最近ね、ちゃんとね、めちゃめちゃお手入れ、してたから、今日の3D配信にね、向けてお手入れしたから、もうツルツルノッツルツルだぜよ。
Recently, I've been taking really good care of it, so for today's 3D stream, it's super sleek!
どう？どう？
How is it?
で、いいでしょ？そう、あとね、ちょっと待ってね。ポコべさんさ、ちょっとポコべさん、すみませんね。
Pretty nice, right? Pokobe, um, excuse me, Pokobe.
こちらの方に来ていただいてもよろしいでござるか？
Would you mind coming over to this side?
ありがとうございます。ちょっとそこで待っててね。ちょっとそこで待っててね。
Thank you very much. Please wait right there.
あとね、ずっとね、見せる機会がなかった、この、あ、ありがとうございます！この後ろのこの、ツバメのしっぽみたいな、このね、おびれみたいな。これ、いいでしょ？
And I haven't had the chance to show this—ah, thank you! This swallow-tail-like obi-fin! Isn't this nice?
あの映り切っててでござるが、いいでしょう。
Well, it's not fully in frame, but that's fine.
ちょっと待って、カメラさんちょっとこれここあやういな。
Wait a minute, camera-san, this part is a bit risky.
ここあやういなちょっと正面からにしよう。ここ正面からにしよう。
This is risky, let's show it from the front. Let's make it from the front.
そう、あとね、そう今までね映り切っててでござるが、あとね
Yes, and also, um, up until now it wasn't fully in frame, but also...
この足ね、足足見て。そう。
these legs, look at the legs. Yes.
かざまね、結構薄っぺらい靴履いてたんだよ。足、いや、いい足でしょ？
Kazama was actually wearing quite thin shoes. My feet—well, nice feet, right?
足の裏も見て。ゴーリー、トリ、え、ちょっと待って、今カメラさん、そのまま今の視点上げたらまずいからね。
Look at the soles of the feet too. Go-ri, to-ri... Wait, camera-san, if you raise the camera angle right now, that's bad.
怒られちゃうからね。上げてだめだよ。で、でもいいでしょう。
I'll get yelled at. Don't raise it. But well, it's fine.
足の裏初公開。
First time showing the soles of my feet!
あぶないあぶないあぶない！あぶないよ！あーもうほんとあぶないな、ちょっと足、足、足、足
Dangerous, dangerous, dangerous! It's dangerous! Ah man, it's really dangerous, wait, my legs, legs, legs, legs...
映んなよでござるが。足、足、足ね、今までの配信でそのほう映ってなかったでござるかな。あ、けっ
Don't show them! My legs, legs, legs, they weren't shown in past streams, were they? Ah, qu-
え、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ねえ見過ぎじゃないですか？ちょっと、あの、ねえ見に、見に見すぎじゃないですか？
Wait, wait, wait, wait, hey, aren't you looking too much? Wait, um, hey, aren't you looking, looking, looking too much?
そんなに足見る？ちょっと。
Do you look at my legs that much? Come on.
あぶないな、ちょっと水着でござる、ダメでござるよ、そんな。
Dangerous, being in swimwear... that's no good, you know.
えっちなのはダメなのです。わかるでござるか？
Ecchi things are not allowed. Do you understand?
ねえ？で、あとね。
Right? And also...
みなどののめっさ気になってたんじゃない今まで？かざまがさ、横から見せないからさ。
Weren't you all super curious up until now? Because Kazama didn't show it from the side.
かざまのさ、厚さ。
Kazama's... thickness.
そう、これが、みなどののこれだからね。このサイズが正しいんだからね。
Yes, this is Minadono's—this is it. This size is the correct one, okay?
オッケー？まあちょっとサラシでね、きゅってんしとるけど。
Okay? Well, it's tightly wrapped with a sarashi, but
今まで触れてこなかったかざまの胸金のサイズはこのようになっております。間違いないように、どうぞよろしくお願いします。
Kazama's chest size, which hasn't been touched upon until now, is like this. Please make sure not to get it wrong.
あでもね本当にね、あの身顔のままでの衣装がすごくね、動きやすくてこうやって改めてね、3Dでこうやっていっぱいね、動けるようになってね、めちゃめちゃ動きやすい。
But really, the costume in its un-binded state is super easy to move in, and now being able to move around so much in 3D like this makes it extremely easy to move!
うおおおおお！うおおおおお！うわ、やばい、カメラさん疲れちゃう。
Whoa! Whoa! Oh no, camera-san is gonna get tired.
うおおおおお！うおおおお！ねえ、やっと動けるようになって嬉しい！ありがとー！
Whoa! Whoa! Hey, I'm so happy I can finally move around! Thank you!
やばいポコベも一緒に動かないと。ね、ポコベね、置物気味になっちゃった。一緒に、ちょっとこうか、ポコベも。
Oh no, Pokobe has to move with me too. Hey, Pokobe became a bit like an ornament. Together, let's put Pokobe here too.
早いの好きだよね、ポコベ。行くぞ！うおおおお！
You like going fast, don't you, Pokobe? Here we go! Whoa!
うおおおお！やばい、酔っちゃうから！ポコベ、ポコベ酔っちゃうかな、大丈夫かな。
Whoa! Oh no, I'll get dizzy! Pokobe, Pokobe might get dizzy, is he okay?
酔った？酔った。ごめんね、ポコベ。
Dizzy? Dizzy. Sorry, Pokobe.
そう、あとね、このステージちょっと今高速で動き回っちゃったんでござるが、そのかざまのこの居る場所。
Yes, and also, I ran around this stage at high speed just now, but this place where Kazama is...
道場です。道場。あ、やべ、ちょっと跳び込んできた。
It's a dojo. A dojo. Ah, oops, I jumped in.
やばい、やばい、やばい。でも道場です。道場、道場。ちょっと紹介していこうかな。
Oh no, oh no, oh no. But it's a dojo. A dojo, a dojo. Let me introduce it a bit.
こっちに、こっちに。見て。見て。かけ軸。
Over here, over here. Look. Look. A hanging scroll.
健康第一！これはね、かざま大将の皆殿にね常日頃言われてるでござるからな。まあ守ろうと思って道場に掲げています。
"Health First"! Kazama Shogun, this is what is said to Minadono every day, so I hung it in the dojo to protect it.
あとね、これはもちろんなんだけど、野菜生活！ででーん！
And then, of course, "Vegetable Life"! Ta-da!
え、これ、いいよスクショ撮って。皆殿これさ、野菜生活。あの野菜普段足りてない方向けにこれを野菜生活をとろうというかざまからののお手渡しです！ででーん！撮った？撮った？撮った？
Hey, this, feel free to take a screenshot. Minadono, this "Vegetable Life"... for those who usually lack vegetables, this is Kazama's offering to take Vegetable Life! Ta-da! Did you take it? Did you take it? Did you take it?
これを壁紙にして皆殿野菜食べるでござるよ。いいでござるから。食べるんだよ。
Make this your wallpaper and eat your vegetables, Minadono. It's fine. You're going to eat them.
あとね鎧兜とかも置いてあったりとか、てかすごいね、いいでしょここ。掃除機兜の小物がねいい感じなでござるよ。暖かいしね。
And also, there's armor and a kabuto helmet placed around, and you know, it's amazing, isn't it nice here? The small items around the cleaning helmet have a nice vibe. It's warm, too.
でね、あとね、あとね。こっちにね。あ、かざまこっちきちゃだめなの。
And then, also, also, also. Over here. Ah, Kazama shouldn't come over here.
太鼓が！太鼓があるんだ！太鼓が！ははは！
A taiko drum! There's a taiko drum! A taiko drum! Haha!
これでいつでも太鼓叩けるぞ。右、右1キロ、左2キロぐらいつけて頑張ろうかなと思います。ここで練習できます。
With this, I can play the taiko drum anytime. I'll do my best attaching about 1 kg to the right and 2 kg to the left. I can practice here.
いやー。そしてね、そしてね、ちょっとこっちこっちこっちこっち。
Yeah. And then, and then, wait, over here, over here, over here.
今まで見せなかったでござるがもう一個隠し扉が、あっちにね。ここ。
Up until now I haven't shown it, but there's another hidden door over there. Here.
ででーん！茄子生活！ででーん！どうよよよよよよよよよ！
Ta-da! "Eggplant Life"! Ta-da! How is that?!
ま、茄子と言ったらね、
Well, when you say eggplant,
なす、毎日食べてるでござるからな。
I eat eggplants every single day, you see.
こちらをね、この道場の入り口に掲げさせていただいて
I've had this displayed right at the entrance of this dojo...
おります！いぇーい！
and here it is! Yay!
いいでしょう、なす。
Nice, right? Eggplant.
いや、やっぱりな、昼食はなすだよな。
Well, as I thought, lunch has got to be eggplant.
これに限るでござる。
Nothing beats it.
でも食べる事の話ばっかりしちゃったでござるが。
Though I just kept talking about eating...
そうだな、せっかく道場だし、そろそろね、
That's right, since it's a dojo, it's about time...
風真がこう日々鍛錬してる所を少しでもね、見せたいなと思います。
I'd like to show you a bit of my daily training.
で、あれ？竹丸…竹丸どこだっけ？
And, huh? Takemaru... Where is Takemaru?
あれ？竹丸。
Huh? Takemaru.
あ、ぽこべぇ！あ、竹丸そっち？オッケー。
Ah, Pokobee! Ah, Takemaru, over there? Okay.
いや、危ない危ない危ない。救う救う。ありがとう。
Phew, close one. I'll save you. Thank you.
いや、無くしたかと思ったでござるよ。
Man, I thought I lost you.
今日ね、あのダンスするからね、外してたんでござるよな。
Today, since I'm going to dance, I had it taken off.
じゃーん、竹丸！ででーん！
Ta-da, Takemaru! Ta-daaa!
って、なにげに初公開じゃないか？ねえ、初公開でござるよな。
Wait, isn't this a first reveal? Right, it's a first reveal!
見える？この輝く銀色の刀。
Can you see it? This gleaming silver blade.
どうそう？妖刀っぽいことしてそう？
How is it? Does it look like a cursed sword?
ででしょででしょ。これでね、悪いやつザキザキ切ってるでござるから。
Right, right? With this, I'm cutting down bad guys left and right.
一回、風真も今一瞬ノーステジキっちゃったけど。
Even Kazama went totally spaced out for a moment there.
かっこいいでしょ！かっこいいでしょ！いぇーい！
Pretty cool, right? Pretty cool, right? Yay!
ね、まね、ちょっと見せびらかしただけでね、お飾りかっ！って言われちゃうから。
See, if I just show it off like this, people will say "Is that just for show?!"
そろそろね、かっこいいとこね、見せていこうかなって、
So it's about time I show you some cool stuff,
いうことで、今日は訓練道具、実は用意してきました。
so I've actually prepared some training equipment for today!
じゃあ、呼ぼうかな、風真の訓練道具、どどーる？道具？道具？行くぞ！
Now, shall I call them? Kazama's training equipment—do-doru? Equipment! Here we go!
それでは、3、2、1、お願いします！
Now then, 3, 2, 1, please!
うわあ！目の前来た！
Whoa! It came right in front of me!
木人、お？
A wooden dummy, oh?
なんだ？回るのか？
What is this? Does it spin?
ぐるぐるぐる、ぐるぐる、お？お？おっ！ちょっと待って！え？これさ、え？
Spinning round and round, oh? Oh? Oh! Wait a minute! Huh? Wait, is this...
ちょっと待って、モザイクかかってんだけど。え？これ、社長の？
Wait, there's a mosaic on this! Huh? Is this the CEO's?
え、口に出していいのこれ？や、や、や、やごー！
Wait, am I allowed to say this out loud? Y-Y-Y-Yagoo!
え、なに？風真のいつも使ってるやつに特別出演ってことでござるか？
What? Is this a special guest appearance on the one Kazama always uses?
いや、ちょっと記念撮影しとこうぜ。社長木人と。行きます。はい、チーズ、いぇい。
Well, let's take a commemorative photo with the CEO dummy. Here we go. Cheese, yay.
あ、もうちょっと寄る？もうちょっとか。はい、チーズ。に、い、き、い。
Ah, get a bit closer? A bit more. Okay, cheese. Ni, i, ki, i.
まね、こんな今仲良く記念撮影してるんでござるが、え、切りを風真は容赦なく切らせていただくでござるよ。ね？いーよ。
Even though we're taking a friendly commemorative photo right now, Kazama will mercilessly slice right through you! Alright.
切りますよ。ぽこべぇ、応援しててんのか？
I'm going to cut. Pokobee, are you cheering me on?
ありがとう。じゃあね、かっこいいとこ、ここにかっこいいとこ見せるから。
Thank you. Well then, I'll show you my cool side right here.
ちょ、見とって。じゃあ風真必殺の
Watch closely. Now, for Kazama's sure-kill...
風真の型、行きます！
Kazama style, here I go!
それでは、行くぞ！
Now then, here we go!
せーの！
Ready, set!
えい！切りました！どうだ？
Hyah! Cut! How's that?
かっこいいでしょ！かっこいいでしょ！見た？今まで見せられなかったでござるからな、
Pretty cool, right? Pretty cool, right? Did you see that? I haven't been able to show you until now,
風真がこんなにこうかっこよく動いてるところ、やっと見せれたわ！
so I was finally able to show you Kazama moving so coolly!
え、1体だけ？
Huh, just one?
いや、まだまだ風真の体力なめてもらっちゃ困るでござるよ。お、どんどん来い、どんどん来い！木人さん、もっとちょうだい！あ、いっぱい来た！やった！
No, you'd be mistaken to underestimate Kazama's stamina. Oh, keep 'em coming! Dummies, give me more! A ton came! Yay!
よし、3体！
Alright, three of them!
まあまあ、3体ぐらいまかせるでござるよ。見とてな、ぽこべぇ。見ててな、みんなの。
Well, I'll handle about three of them. Watch, Pokobee. Watch, everyone.
行くぞ！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, set!
行くぞ！えい！切れてるか？はっ！
Here we go! Hah! Did I cut it? Ha!
おお、切れた！ちょっと、ちょっと時間経ったら、ちょっと時間経ったら。
Oh, it cut! Wait, after a little time passes...
よし、じゃあ行くぞ！えい！
Alright, then here I go! Ha!
おらららららららららららららら、もっともっと、切る！切れろ！おりゃ！
Oraoraoraoraoraora, more and more, cut! Cut! Hah!
切れろ！こっちだ！切れろ！おりゃ！おっしゃ！
Cut! Over here! Cut! Hah! Yes!
よかった！ちゃんと切れた！おっけーおっけー。
Great! I cut it properly! Okay, okay.
切れだ、おっけーおっけーおっけーおっけー。まだまだね、3体相手はなかなか...
Cut, okay, okay, okay. Still, facing three at once is quite...
体力を使ったでござるが、
I used up my stamina, but
まだ！まだいけるよ！まだいけるよ！
still! I can still go! I can still go!
風魔はいけるでござるよ！
Kazama can still go!
どんとこい！
Bring it on!
おっ、ちょっと待て。
Oh, wait a second.
わあ…わあちょっと待て。1、2、3、4、5…！五か！
Whoa... wait a second. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5...! Five!
いけるか？
Can I do this?
正面、やっぱね、月とかも見せたいでござるからね。
For the front, I want to show the moon and all.
月個別に、正面のやつを、月破壊するってでござる。
For each moon, the front one, I'll destroy the moon.
じゃ、行きますよ。
Alright, here I go.
それでは、行きます。
Well then, here I go.
いーーーーー…よいしょっ！
Reaaaaady... heave-ho!
おっしゃあ！見た。見たでござるか？
Alright! Did you see that? Did you see that?
他のね、母体も…はっ！
The other... bodies too... Ha!
おっ！はっ！
Oh! Ha!
はい！もういっちょ！オッケー！いっきまーすよー！
Yes! One more! Okay! Here we go!
はい！…はーい！
Yes! ...Right!
はっ！切れたけど…なんやつ、まだ地に足がついているな。
Ha! I cut it, but... wait, it's still touching the ground.
うえ、くらえっ！こっ！はっ！
Take this! Hah! Ha!
うわあ…強い！
Whoa... so strong!
だがしかし切れたことに間違いはないでござるな。
But still, there's no doubt I cut it.
いやでも見た？見た？こんなに動ける風魔見れる機会、
Did you see? A chance to see Kazama move like this—
今まで本当になかったし、風魔も見せれてね、めちゃくちゃ嬉しいでござるな。
I've never had before, and showing you Kazama too, I'm super happy.
いやあ、ありがとうー！
Man, thank you so much!
体幹の風魔もね、でも合計、9体？9体を相手にするのは結構疲れたでござるな。
Kazama's core too... 9 bodies? Dealing with 9 bodies was quite tiring.
そろそろね、疲れてきたし、ちょっとおやつ食べて、おにぎり食べてね、休憩しようかこれ。
It's about time, I'm getting tired, let's eat snacks, rice balls, and take a break.
ね、休憩しょ、休憩にしましょう！
Right, let's take a break, let's take a break!
ふう。
Phew.
はやく人参でござるか？
Is it carrot time already?
ん？ぽこべ？
Hm? Pokobe?
ん？
Hm?
貴様！何やつ！
You scoundrel! Who goes there?!
っ！あぶない！おっとっとっとっと…！危ない！
Watch out! Whoa whoa whoa...! Dangerous!
なかなか腕が立つようでござるな。お客様と行った感じでもなさそうでござるし。
You seem quite skilled. And it doesn't look like you're a customer.
仕方ない。
Can't be helped.
ここは風魔が制裁してあげるでござるよ！いくぞ！
Kazama will punish you right here! Here I go!
くらっ！
Take this!
はっ！
Ha!
ふう…
Phew...
さよ。
Sayo.
どこ行った？
Where'd she go?
さよ。
Sayo.
おっ、おっ、おっ、さよ。
Oh, oh, oh, Sayo.
あっ、あったあったあったさよ。
Ah, there you are, Sayo.
よかった、無くしたかと思ったでござるよ。
Thank goodness, I thought I lost you.
まあまあまあ、でも風魔にかかればこれくらい朝飯前でござるな。
Well, for Kazama, this is a piece of cake before breakfast.
ねっ？
Right?
ふう。
Phew.
敵も倒せたし、
I defeated the enemy too,
今日は頑張ったでござるな、風魔！
Kazama worked hard today!
ねっ？ちゃんと頑張ってたでござるよな。見てた？ねっ？見てた？
Right? I worked really hard, didn't I? Were you watching?
いやちょっと出すぎた…違う違う違いすぎた！ごめんでござるよみんな！ごめんね！ごめんね！
Whoa, too much... No, way too much! Sorry everyone! Sorry!
でもちょっとね、頑張りすぎたから休憩しつつ…あれ？
Since I worked a bit too hard, while taking a break... Huh?
お腹空いたけど、さっき茄子食べ損ねたんだよな。
I'm hungry, but I missed out on eating eggplant earlier.
おっ、ぽこべー！
Oh, Pokobe!
ぽこべー、ありがとう！茄子持ってきてくれたでござるか？
Pokobe, thank you! Did you bring me some eggplant?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
背中にじゃあそのチョッチェの茄子をね、もらえまして。
And so, I received those little eggplants from your back.
はい、よいしょっと。え、ありがとう！
Here, heave-ho. Oh, thank you!
ね、さっき休憩しようって言ってね、ご飯食べ損ねたでござるからさ。
You know, earlier I said let's take a break and missed eating.
一緒に食べよっか！ねっ？
Let's eat together! Right?
ちゃんと湿気して、いただきよ。
Let's make sure it's moist and dig in.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあ、せーのっ！いただきまーす！
Then, ready, set! Bon appétit!
あむあむあむ…
Nom nom nom...
うまい！うまい！
Delicious! Delicious!
やっぱね、茄子はね、生に限るでござるな！ねえ、ぽこべ？
As expected, eggplant is best eaten raw, right Pokobe?
ね、ぽこべも食べた？食べたでござるな。
Right, did Pokobe eat too? You ate, didn't you.
いや本当にね、いろんなことが
Man, truly, so many things...
もうこのちょっとの時間で、あったでござるしね。
...have happened in just this short amount of time.
腹ごしらえもしたところで、
And right after getting a bite to eat—
そう、よいしょ。
That's right, there we go.
実はね風真、今回このお披露目でどうしてもやりたいなって思ってたことがありまして、
Actually, Kazama, for this debut reveal, there was something I really, really wanted to do...
実はこれのために、舞踊を練習してきましたー！
...and for that very reason, I practiced a traditional dance!
で、がんばったんでござるよ。がんばったところをね、ちょっと見てもらいたくて、
I worked really hard on it, and I wanted you all to see how well I did.
今日は特別に、披露しよっかな、披露しよっかなと思います。
So today, I'd like to show it off specially for you.
そう。このね、じゃじゃーん！
That's right. With this... ta-da!
これを使って、舞踊を踊っていきたいと思いまーす！
I'm going to dance using this!
よし、ちょっと緊張するけど、見ててくださいね、皆殿。
Alright, I'm a little nervous, but please watch, everyone.
それでは、準備できたみたいなので、演奏開始！
Well then, it looks like I'm ready. Performance, start!
皆殿、どうだったでござるか？
How was that, everyone?
一応練習してきたけど、正直緊張で手足爪先どこもかしこもプルプルだったでござる！
I practiced hard, but honestly, I was trembling from head to toe with nervousness!
素敵だった？かっこよかった？コメントが、コメントがめっちゃ、コメントがめっちゃ！
Was it wonderful? Was it cool? The chat is going crazy!
ありがとーー！
Thank you so much!
あ、鈴三昧はうるさいね。ちょっとじゃ鈴はしまっちゃいます。バイバーイ！
Ah, the bells are noisy. Let's put the bells away. Bye-bye!
見せたかったものも見せれて、身体は大満足なんだけど、おっ、おっ！
I got to show you what I wanted, and I'm super satisfied, but... oh? Oh!
ぽこべえ、見守っててくれたでござるか？よいしょ。
Pokobee, were you watching over me? There we go.
いや、ぽこべえね、ずっと練習してたからね、これね、皆殿に今日見せたよ。ぽこべえもありがとね！
You see, Pokobee, I've been practicing so hard, and I got to show everyone today. Thanks to you too, Pokobee!
でもね、そう、もう一個ね、そう、もう一箇所ね、皆殿をお連れしたい場所があるので、行ってこようと思うんだけど。
But you know, there's one more place I want to take everyone to, so I thought about going there next.
ぽこべえ、お留守番しててでござるか？
Pokobee, will you stay and watch the house?
いやだ？いやだなの？
You don't want to? You don't want to?
ちょ、そこはうんて言うとこでしょ？ううんじゃないでしょ？
Wait, isn't that where you're supposed to say yes? Not 'no'!
大丈夫！ね、また今度連れてってあげるから。今日はちょっとね、待ってて。ぽこべえ頑張ってくるから見てて。
It's okay! I'll take you next time. Just wait a bit today. Pokobee, I'll do my best, so watch me.
オッケー？よし、じゃあちょっとぽこべえ行ってくるから、ぽこべえありがとね！
Okay? Alright, then I'm off, Pokobee, thank you!
あーぽこべえ！ありがとうね！
Ah, Pokobee! Thank you so much!
取れた？皆殿の、今日のぽこべえとのツーショット撮れた？
Did you get it? Did you get a photo with Pokobee today, everyone?
よし、じゃあ行ってくるねぽこべえ、写真撮影ありがとう！
Alright, I'm off then, Pokobee, thanks for the photo shoot!
よし！というわけで、気を撮りなおしまして、もう一箇所皆殿のお連れしたい場所に連れて行きます！お連れしたい場所に連れて行きます？日本語変だな。まあとりあえず一緒に行こう！というわけで、
Alright! And with that, let's reset our mood and head to the next place I want to take everyone! Wait, the next place I want to take you? My Japanese is weird. Well, anyway, let's go together! So, with that...
せーの、いくぞ！うおおおおお！
Ready, set, go! Whoa-oh-oh-oh!
みなさんお待たせしました！
Everyone, thank you for waiting!
新しいお披露目席来たよー！
The new reveal stage is here!
すごくない！？大自然だよ！すごいでしょう！？
Isn't it amazing?! It's pure nature! Isn't it great?!
というわけで歌わせていただきますよ ペンライトといっぱい振ってくださいね
So without further ado, I'll be singing for you! Please wave your penlights lots, okay?
フル準備大丈夫でございますか？できてる？振ってね！
Are you ready for the full setup? Is everyone ready? Wave them!
いくよー！
Here we go!
梅雨が明けるまであとどれくらい？
How long until the rainy season ends?
まだ紫陽花の光る朝 君の愚痴
Still, the hydrangeas glow in the morning, your complaints
夏の足音はすぐそこまで
The footsteps of summer are just around the corner
ねぇ 迎えに行ってって僕を急かす
Hey, hurry and go welcome me, you urge me on
君に言われるがまま路地を抜け
Passing through the alley just as you tell me
あの時の坂を越え 虹を越え
Over the hill of that time, over the rainbow
まだ誰もいない夏の空を
The summer sky where no one is yet
全部全部二人占めにするんだ
We'll have all to ourselves, every bit of it
ああ なんて君は笑ってたよな
Ah, how you were smiling
遠い夏の記憶
Memories of a distant summer
もう逢えなくても 二度と帰れなくても
Even if we can never meet again, even if we can never return
それは美しい
That is beautiful
僕らだけの夏だったろう
It must have been our summer alone
さよなら i love you それで全て
Goodbye, I love you, with that, everything
終わってしまうような 僕らじゃないだろう
We aren't the kind of people whose story ends like that
変わらないな 空も星も その泣き顔も
Nothing changes, neither the sky, the stars, nor that crying face
っていつか君と また笑えますように
Praying that someday I can laugh with you again
そりゃ色々あっただろう 今もあるだろう
Sure, there have been things, and there still are
でも笑いながら生きていく それが人世だって
But living on while smiling, that's life as they say
そんな単細胞になれたら どれだけ良いかって
If only I could become that simple-minded, how great would that be
過ぎ去って行く日々に意味は無い
Days passing by hold no meaning
なら明日の僕は僕じゃない
Then the me of tomorrow is not me
そんな筈はないだろう
That can't be right
泣いていたって空は晴れるよ
Even if you're crying, the sky will clear up
君が濡らしたって滲まないほど 乾いていたって空は星を降らすから
Even if you soak it or if it's dry, the sky makes stars fall
まぁ、生きていくよ
Well, I'll keep living on
I know this sky loves you いずれ全て
I know this sky loves you, eventually everything
変わってしまったって空は青いだろう! 忘れないさ
Even if it has changed, the sky must be blue! I won't forget
でもまた出逢えますように って生きてくよ
Hoping we'll meet again, I'll keep on living.
君は笑っていて
Please keep on smiling.
えー！というわけで、開幕曲たなごころでした！
Eep! So that was our opening song, "Tanagokoro"!
というわけで、歌わせていただきました！
And so we got to sing it!
開会式でございます！
That's the opening ceremony!
緊張したー！緊張したー！はい、どうだったでしょうか？
I was so nervous! So nervous! Yes, how was it?
そしてね、見て、そう、改めてなんですけど、
And you see, look—well, to say it again,
開幕ステージすごくないって叫んじゃったんですが、
I shouted about how amazing the opening stage is,
見てくださいこのステージ、すごくない！？
but please look at this stage, isn't it amazing?!
すごいっしょ！すごいくない！？もう大自然の中に作ってもらいました、この水上ステージを！
Isn't it amazing?! They built this water stage right in the middle of great nature!
すごい！月も今日はきれいだ！
Amazing! The moon is so beautiful tonight too!
そうね、もう本当に大きい滝の前にこうどすって無理やり立ててもらって、
That's right, they shoved it right in front of a huge waterfall,
風真のお気に入りポイントがね、後ろに風車をいっぱいさしてもらったんでございますよ。見えるかな？風車色風車色！いいでしょ？
and Kazama's favorite point is, they let me put lots of pinwheels in the back. Can you see them? Colorful pinwheels! Isn't it nice?
あとは、このね、水上に浮いてる灯籠がね、なんとも幻想的でしょ？皆さんの。いいでしょ？いいでしょ？いいでしょ、どやどやどやどや。
And also, these floating lanterns on the water, aren't they fantastical? Everyone's. Isn't it nice? Ta-da!
はい。そしてね、もう本当にね、風車といえば和ということで、
Yes. And really, speaking of pinwheels, it's Japanese style,
竹やら何やら木材で立派なステージ作ってもらいました！すごい！ありがとうございます！
so they built a splendid stage out of bamboo and various wood! Amazing! Thank you so much!
今日はね、残りはここでいっぱい練習してきた歌と踊りをね、披露できたらと思いますので、最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね！
Today, I hope to show you the songs and dances I've practiced so much right here, so please enjoy it all the way to the end!
はい。というわけで、いやすごいまだ緊張するけど、まだ他にも曲はいっぱい残ってるんでござるから、見せていきたいと思います！次の曲、それでは皆さんの準備はいいですか？聞いてくださいでござる。曲は、「ハイドアンド・シーク」！
Yes. So, man, I'm still super nervous, but there are lots of other songs left, so I want to show them to you! For the next song, are you all ready? Please listen. The song is "Hide and Seek"!
嫌われる事が怖くて 僕は僕は僕を隠した
Afraid of being hated, I hid myself away.
誰かの陰口が痛くて 僕は耳を耳を塞いだ
Someone's gossip hurt so much, I covered my ears.
本当の僕は汚くって きっとみんな僕を嫌うから
The real me is foul, and surely everyone would hate me.
本当の僕は隠しちゃって 綺麗なとこだけ見せてたんだ
So I hid the real me and only showed the pretty parts.
ある日誰かの言葉も全部 嘘に聞こえて悲しくなった
One day, everyone's words sounded like lies and made me sad.
そうだ僕の事を嫌うのは 誰かじゃなくて見せたくない方の僕だ
That's right, the one who hates me isn't anyone else, but the me I don't want to show.
もういいかい ねえまだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet.
本当の僕が恋しくなって
I started longing for my true self.
もう一回呼びかけてみるけど まだ見つからないよ
I call out once more, but still can't find it.
ほらもういいかい ねえまだだよ
Hey, are you ready? Not yet.
その内声も届かなくなって
Soon my voice stopped reaching out.
もう一体僕は誰なのか 分からないんだ
I don't even know who I am anymore.
鬼さんこちら手の鳴る方へ 君は此処にしちゃいけないから
Ogre-san, this way to the clapping—you mustn't be here.
そんな事告げる僕の方が よっぽど君より鬼みたいだ
The me telling you that seems much more like an ogre than you.
遠く暗い世界に落ちた 君が最後に一言言った
Fallen into a distant, dark world, you said one last word.
君が僕を捨てて手に入れる 誰かの愛は
The love someone gets after throwing me away
見せかけだけの愛だ
Is just fake love.
今君に もういいかい ねえ まだだよ
Now, to you... "Ready yet?" "Not yet."
僕は誰かに愛されたくって
I wanted to be loved by someone,
もう何回嘘に嘘を重ねれば 救われるかな
How many more lies must I pile up to be saved?
ほら もういいかい ねえ まだだよ
Hey, "Ready yet?" "Not yet."
その内僕が僕じゃなくなって
Before long, I stopped being myself,
もう一体何がしたいのかさえも わからないんだ
And I don't even know what I want anymore.
明日君に 打ち明けるんだ
Tomorrow, I'll confess to you.
僕は卑怯で 臆病だって
That I'm a coward and timid,
誰かに嫌われる事よりも
More than being hated by someone,
何十倍も辛い事に気付いたよ
I realized it's dozens of times more painful.
今僕に もういいかい ねえ まだだよ
Now, to me... "Ready yet?" "Not yet."
本当の君はどこにいますか
Where are you, the real you?
もう何回君のことを信じれば 絶ち切れるかな
How many times must I believe in you to break free?
今君に もういいかい ねえ もうちょっと
Now, to you... "Ready yet?" "Just a little more..."
僕の世界が君に近づいて
My world gets closer to you,
もう一回呼びかけてみたら 君の声が聞こえた
When I called out one more time, I heard your voice.
ほら もういいかい ねえ もういいよ
See, "Ready yet?" "Yeah, I'm ready."
その内空も少し色付いて
Before long, the sky also colors a little,
もう一歩足を踏み出したら ほらね やっと
If I take one more step forward, see, finally...
君を見つけた
I found you.
愛される事を望んで
Wishing to be loved,
僕は 僕は 僕は隠した
I hid myself, myself, myself.
痛んだ傷口を塞いで
Covering up my painful wounds,
僕は君を 君を愛した
I loved you, I loved you.
はいというわけでハイドアンドシークでした！
There you have it, that was "Hide and Seek"!
いやさすがにね、ちゃんとダンスをすると暑くなるんだろうなと思って。
I figured dancing properly would really make you work up a sweat.
じゃん。
Ta-da!
羽織を、うっう、上着、羽織を脱ぎました！
I took off my haori, um, my jacket, my haori!
ちょっと何気に初公開なんてござるよな。ちょっとじゃ、ちょっとカメラさんに見て貰おうかな。
This is actually my first time revealing this, isn't it? Let's have the camera take a look.
ちょっとじゃあ、見てー。
So, take a look!
情報は意外とね、サムネイルとかで見たことあるかもしれないんでござるが、ちょっと後ろ見てよっかな。
You might have seen the front in thumbnails, but let's check out the back.
こういう感じで、お供え…お供えじゃない、お供えしております。背中がバッチリだね。
Like this, offering... no, not offering, I'm presenting it. My back looks great.
あ、ちょっと待って、そう。これスパッツね、これなんて言ったらいいんだ？おへその上までで止まってるんでござるから、若干ちょっと隙間があるんだよね。ちょっと恥ずかしいね
Oh, wait, these spats... they stop right above my belly button, so there's a gap. A bit embarrassing!
涼しい！動きやすい！
It's cool! Easy to move in!
そう、というわけでね、踊らせて歌わせていただいたんでござるが、どうでしたか？
So, I sang and danced to that, how was it?
いや、ずっとね、ダンスレッスンをね、頑張ってやっていて、一曲こうしっかりね踊れるようになるまでに練習頑張ったんでござるからね、
I've been working hard at dance lessons to be able to dance a whole song properly,
見せるのめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！ちょっとね、閉じたりもしたけど、めっちゃ緊張したー
So I'm super happy to show it! I messed up a bit, but I was so nervous!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
え、なんか待ってね、今速報が、速報が…あ！ なんかTwitterのトレンドが1位らしい！
Wait, breaking news... Oh! Apparently Twitter trends are at #1!
え、すごい！ありがとうございます！ありがとうございますございます！やった、嬉しい！めちゃくちゃ皆さんも見てくれて、ツイートしてくれてありがとうございます。たくさん写真撮ってツイートしてくださいね。
Amazing! Thank you so much everyone for watching, tweeting, and taking photos!
イェーイ、ありがとうございます！嬉しいでござるな。
Yay, thank you! I'm so glad.
なんか頑張ってきて良かったなってめちゃくちゃ思います。本当にありがとうございます！ちょっと待って、水飲んでいいか。
I really feel like working hard was worth it. Thank you so much! Wait, can I drink some water?
ちょ、水飲んでいいですか？ちょっと水飲みます。ちょっと水飲みます。飲む。
Can I drink some water? Let me drink some water.
飲みました！
I had a drink!
いや、いっぱい動いたからな。
Well, I moved around a lot.
ま、でもね、風真の体力はまだまだ続きますよ。
Well, but Kazama's stamina is still going.
このお披露目もまだまだ続きますので、次の曲に行きたいと思います。
And this debut stream continues further, so I'd like to move on to the next song.
次は、特にメン限でも練習してた、あの曲を練習してお披露目のためにも持ってきたので聴いてほしいです。
Next, I practiced this song especially on member-only streams, and brought it for the public debut too, so I'd love for you to listen.
それでは次の曲、聴いてください。
With that, please listen to the next song.
心做し
Kokoronashi
ねえ、もしも全て投げ捨てられたら
Hey, if everything could be thrown away,
笑って生きることが楽になるの？
would laughing and living become easy?
また胸が痛くなるから
My chest starts hurting again,
もう何も言わないでよ
so please don't say anything anymore.
ねえ、もしも全て忘れられたら
Hey, if everything could be forgotten,
泣かないで生きることも楽になるの？
would living without crying become easy?
でもそんな事できないから
But since I can't do that,
もう何も見せないでよ
please don't show me anything anymore.
君にどれだけ近づいても
No matter how close I get to you,
僕の心臓は一つだけ
I only have one heart.
酷いよ 酷いよ、もういっそ僕の体を
It's cruel, it's cruel—so crush my body instead,
壊して 引き裂いて 好きなようにしてよ
break it, tear it apart, do whatever you like with it.
叫んで 掻搏いて 瞼を腫らしても
Even if I scream, scratch, and swell my eyelids,
まだ君は僕のことを抱きしめて離さない
you still hold me close and won't let go.
もういいよ
Enough is enough.
ねえ、もしも僕の願いが叶うなら
Hey, if my wish were to come true,
君と同じものが欲しいんだ
I'd want the same thing as you.
でも僕には存在しないから
But since it doesn't exist for me,
じゃあせめて此処に来てよ
then at least come over here.
君にどれだけ愛されても
No matter how much you love me,
僕の心臓は一つだけ
I only have one heart.
やめてよ やめてよ、優しくしないでよ
Stop it, stop it, don't be so gentle with me.
どうしても僕には理解ができないよ
No matter what, I just can't understand.
痛いよ 痛いよ、言葉で教えてよ
It hurts, it hurts, tell me in words.
こんなの知らないよ 独りにしないで
I don't know anything like this, don't leave me alone.
酷いよ 酷いよ、もういっそ僕の体を
It's cruel, it's cruel—so crush my body instead,
壊して 引き裂いて 好きなようにしてよ
break it, tear it apart, do whatever you like with it.
叫んで 掻搏いて 瞼を腫らしても
Even if I scream, scratch, and swell my eyelids,
まだ君は僕のことを抱きしめて離さない
you still hold me close and won't let go.
もういいよ
Enough is enough.
ねえ、もしも僕に心があるなら
Hey, if I had a heart,
どうやってそれを見つければいいの？
how would I go about finding it?
少し微笑んで君が言う
You smile a little and say,
「それはね、ここにあるよ」
"It's right here, you see."
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、心無しでしたー。
And that was "Kokoronashi".
あ、コメント欄が泣いてる！
Ah, the comment section is crying!
泣かないで、拍手もいっぱいありがとう！
Don't cry! Thank you for all the applause!
ずっと練習してたでござるからな、歌えてとっても嬉しいです。
I'm so happy to be able to sing it.
この3Dお披露目配信のことはずっと言いたくて...
I've wanted to talk about this 3D debut stream...
面接とかで練習してても言えないなと思いながら。
Thinking "I can't say it yet" during practice.
ずっとこの曲で大丈夫かなっていんな思いもあったんですけど
I had many thoughts wondering if this song was okay,
無事みんなに喜んでもらえてとっても嬉しいです！
but I'm so happy everyone enjoyed it!
よし、心臓バクバク、
Okay, my heart is pounding,
だけど…一回水飲んでいいでござるか？
but... can I take a sip of water?
ちょっと水いってきます！
Hold on, I'm going to get some water!
やばい！足りてないんだよ、酸素も水も！
Oh no! I'm running out of oxygen and water!
さすがのフィジカルおばけ風真いろはでも来るものがあるでござるな。
Even for physical monster Kazama Iroha, it hits you.
今日は楽しんでもらえましたかみんなとの？
Did you enjoy today, everyone?
あっという間でござるな、そしてホロックス次のメンバーも3D化！
It flew by. Next HoloX 3D is coming!
知ってるでござるよな、それではどどん！
Of course you do, so here we go!
はーい！沙花叉クロヱ！3Dお披露目！
Hi! Sakamata Chloe! 3D reveal!
次は沙花叉、6月13日月曜日20時からありますよー！
Next is Sakamata, June 13th at 20:00!
楽しみだね、すごいね楽しみ！
I'm so excited, super excited!
でもサムネイルのページやばいな、大丈夫なのかな？
That thumbnail page is crazy, is that okay?
絶対確認チェックしてくださいね、一緒に見るぞー！
Be sure to check it out, let's watch together!
風真の3Dお披露目を見てくださった皆さん、本当ありがとうございます！
Thank you to everyone who watched my 3D reveal!
色々至らないところやご迷惑おかけしたりとか、やらかしがちでござるが…
I've had shortcomings and caused trouble often,
この日のために一生懸命準備してまいりました！
but I prepared with all my heart for this day!
見守っていてくれたらとても嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you keep watching over me.
これからも風真いろはについてきてくださいねー！
Please continue to follow Kazama Iroha!
というわけで、次が残念ながら最後の曲になります。
And with that, this is our final song.
みんながずっと見たい、聴きたいと言ってくれたあの曲を練習してきました！
I practiced the song you all wanted to hear!
最後までしっかりと見届けてくれたら嬉しいです、それでは聴いてください！
I'd be happy if you watched until the end!
好きになって！もっと！
Become my fan! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is "with a love-filled flying kiss"!
気のせいじゃない目は合ってるよ
It's not my imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート♡作って恋しちゃって下さい！
Make a heart and fall in love with me!
♡作って恋しちゃって下さい！
♡ Make a heart and fall in love, please!
やれること何でもします
I'll do whatever it takes.
NG無しで体当たり挑戦
Taking on any challenge head-on with no restrictions.
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
The anti comments I found from vanity searches,
ふざけんな！…誰より分かってるし
"Don't mess with me!"... I know that better than anyone.
でも大丈夫ステージに立てばみんながいる
But it's alright, when I stand on this stage, everyone is here.
行くよ！
Here we go!
好きになって！
Fall in love with me!
もっと！私を見て！
More! Look at me!
もっと！恩返しは
More! Returning the favor with...
“愛のこもった投げキスで”とりこにする！
"A love-filled blowing kiss" to captivate you!
もっと！夢を見せる！
More! I'll show you dreams!
もっと！楽しんでって
More! Enjoy yourselves!
愛のこもったスペシャルナイト ファンサしちゃうぞ
A love-filled special night, I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them.
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
Scandals are still a bit too early,
裏切りません！宣言しときます
I won't betray you! I declare it!
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment.
ふざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
"Don't mess with me!" I'll win with pure skill.
だから辞めない 負けず嫌いな私はいる
That's why I won't quit, my stubborn, competitive self is here.
行くよ！
Here we go!
こぶし上げて！
Raise your fists!
もっと！汗をかいて！
More! Work up a sweat!
もっと！恩返しは
More! Returning the favor with...
“愛のこもったこざるビームで”大歓声！
"A love-filled kozaru beam" for loud cheers!
もっと！まだまだねぇ？
More! Not yet, right?
もっと！受け止めてね
More! Catch my feelings!
愛のこもったわがままソング ファンサしちゃうぞ
A love-filled selfish song, I'll give you fan service!
はぁ…終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Ah... the end is drawing near, it's lonely.
寂しいね
It's lonely.
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も次もまた会えるよね？
Will we meet again and again next time too?
優しさに溢れている言葉も 心ない誰かの言葉さえも
Whether words overflowing with kindness, or even the heartless words of someone,
必要なんだ必要なんだ 強くなろう
They're necessary, necessary, I'll become stronger!
好きに叫べ！
Scream as you like!
もっと！楽しんじゃえ！
More! Enjoy yourselves to the fullest!
もっと！忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
More! Don't forget, hoping this becomes a special day.
共に歌おうずっと！共に歩もうずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
合言葉は とびっきり の l・o・v・e
Our password is an extraordinary L-O-V-E!
好きになって！
Fall in love with me!
もっと！私を見て！
More! Look at me!
もっと！恩返しは
More! Returning the favor with...
“愛のこもった投げキスで”とりこにする！
"A love-filled blowing kiss" to captivate you!
もっと！夢を見せる！
More! I'll show you dreams!
もっと！楽しんでって
More! Enjoy yourselves!
愛のこもったスペシャルナイト ファンサしちゃうぞ
A love-filled special night, I'll give you fan service!
というわけで、風真いろは3Dをお披露目来て下さった皆さま、ありがとうございます！
So, thank you everyone who came to witness Kazama Iroha's 3D debut!
皆さまのこと噛んじゃった
I tripped over my words about everyone—
皆さまのこと大好きでござるよ！ありがとう！
I love you all so much! Thank you!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!